PARVEEN KUMAR

Full stack Javascript Developer +9 Years

Email: paulparveen01@gmail.com

Contact: +91-9780084632 Skype: parveenpaul24

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/parveenpal

Imaginative, collaborative Software Engineer with 9+ year's experience, positively guide the customer experience through innovative and solutions-based support. Empathetic and analytical, supports company-wide initiatives by responding to issues in a timely and friendly manner.

Core competencies

Collaborative, Time Management, Software Engineering, Full Stack Web Development, Software Development, Problem Solving, Technical Leadership, Team player, Empathy, Written & Verbal Communication

Technical skills

NodeJs, ExpressJS, Typescript, Jest, VueJs, Javascript, Oops, MVC, Rest API, jQuery, Ajax, Json, Npm, Git, MySql, Sequelize, Elasticsearch, Jira, AWS (S3, RDS, Lambda function, API Gateway, Cloudfront, Cloudwatch, DynamoDB, EC2, Cognito), Serverless application, three-layer architecture web app.

Professional experience

Cognizant Technology solutions

Sr. Associate - Projects 05/2021 - present

ThinkSys Software Pvt. Ltd

Sr. Software Engineer Nov, 2019 - 05/2021

Q3 Technologies

Sr. Software Engineer 05/2017 - 07/2019

Agile Continental

Technology Developer 07/2016 - 05/2017

Evolvan Info sol pvt ltd

Software Engineer 10/2014 - 07/2016

TCY Online Learning Sol (P) Ltd

PHP Developer 03/2013 - 09/2014

Projects

Title: Dental Assessment

Description: Dental Assessment website based on uploaded selfies. Teeth as a subject part being cropped using AWS Face API and after it's created collage for all images. It's a serverless web application using AWS lambda function. Microservices, Monolithic & three-tier Architecture.

Technologies : VueJs as frontend & NodeJs, AWS as a backend. API Gateway, DynamoDB, CloudFront, Lambda function, S3

Role & Responsibilities:

- Worked on both Frontend & Backend development
- Involved in coding and database schema design
- Worked on creating API using AWS API Gateway and Lambda function
- Direct interaction with client for discussion of tasks & Requirements

Url : https://d24e4p0y2o78hs.cloudfront.net/

Title: Gaming Project

Description: This project deals in games in Canada & USA

Technologies: NodeJs, VueJs, Javascript, AWS, MySql, Html, Css

Role & Responsibilities:

- Ongoing development and demand support on the site
- Managing & working with dev team to resolve task bug & blockers and guiding them to follow best practices
- Attending daily client meeting for discussion of tasks & Requirements

Url: Undisclosed

Title: Health Survey Application (WHO)

Description: Online health application promoted by World Health Organization to conduct TB surveys across India and store its patient data to investigate and generate various reports.

Technologies: NodeJs, MySQL, Nginx, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax

Role & Responsibilities:

- Ongoing development
- Involved in maintenance of existing application and enhancement on coding modules
- Finding and fixing bugs

Url: Admin panel protected url

Education

Batchelor in Technology – Computer science – 2012

I hereby declare that the above particulars are correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

DATE: 05-07-2021